Open up the Sunshine app. And we'll create a
new file for our ForecastAdapter, which extends cursor adapter. We
provided you with a gist of code to get started
below. The code overrides the newView method, where it inflates
the list item forecast layout XML. It also provides
an implementation for bindView, where it reads from the cursor,
and updates the layout. For example, from the cursor, we
read the weather forecast description. Then we go and find
the text view for that within the view hierarchy of the
list item layout. We look for the text view with the id
list_item_forecast_textview. Then we update the
textview with the right description. We
also left some to dos in the code. So, go ahead and
copy over the file and then finish the to dos. In
the current implementation of the app, all dates are displayed the same.
In the wireframes though, you'll notice that we have a more friendly
date format. In the gist we also included some helper methods and
strings for date formatting. That's because in our current
implementation, all the dates are displayed in the same way.
In the wireframes though, we have a more friendly date
format. Such as today, tomorrow, Wednesday, Thursday, etc. Here's that
logic for what the helper method does to get the
friendly date string. If it's this week it says today,
or tomorrow, or the day of the week. If it's
more than a week out then we use the format
Monday, June 8th and so on. Once you finish the
to dos and you added the helper methods and strings,
then go ahead and replace the simple cursor adapter with
a forecast adapter. After you compile and run the app it'll
look the same as before with only one list item
view type shown, except now it's using a ForecastAdapter and
now it has better date descriptions. I know that I
promised you that cursor adapters could handle multiple item view types,
so we'll do that in the next step.